Joshua Bennet

An aspiring software developer

- South-West, England
- hello@joshbennet.com
- joshbennet.com
- JoshuaBennet
- in Joshua Bennet

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Scrum Master

Scrum Alliance

HOBBIES

Sport

I have been passionate about many different sports including fencing, rowing, volleyball, powerlifting and others.

Traveling

I like to travel to see friends and experience the history of the world. Used to live in the US and Slovakia. In January 2019 I summited Mt. Kilimanjaro.

Reading Novels

Some of my favourites would be the Ringworld series, The Kingkiller Chronicle, Brandon Sanderson in general, and lots more.

All kinds of Games

Some of my favourites would be Dungeons and Dragons, Everdell (boardgame), any RPG (Oblivion, Witcher, Cyberpunk, etc).

REFERENCES

Rayna Bozhkova

Mentor/Trainer at iO Academy.

rayna.bozhkova@io-academy.uk

Tara Mead

Operations Director at Strategic Insurance Services Ltd.

Will be able to offer contact at request.

Resourceful and dedicated full-stack developer, hungry to learn more. My immersion in technology started early, surrounded by a community of tech driven people. In my spare time I like reading novels, going to the cinema, and exercising. Currently studying at iO Academy, due to graduate in October.

PROJECTS

I recently studied software development at iO Academy, during my time there and since I worked on a range of projects, both individual and in a scrum team. Below is a small selection of my favourites, take a look at my portfolio for the rest.

Email Client front-end

React app that consumes an existing API

During this project I used **React** to build an email client from spec utilising an **existing API**. Via the use of **Scrum** we as a team constructed a crisp responsive front-end.

Through the use of **Git** we **peer reviewed** and merged our worked keeping code quality high. We were working from a high fidelity wireframe supplied by the product owner, from this we used **Bootstrap** to form the visual experience to the desired style. The use of **CSS** and **HTML** was also key during this project as we needed to get the positioning just right, which required us to go beyond **Bootstrap** on some occasions.

Social media platform

OOP Listing App in PHP

For this project the aim was to produce high-quality code and follow good **architectural patterns** using **PHP**. The app itself was a social media platform utilising a **SQL** database, which started off as an **Agile** planning session to construct a robust wireframe and app architecture to follow. The sign up page was hardened with **validation** and **sanitisation** against dangerous inputs and to strip tags in case of **HTML** input. The project followed **OOP** and **SOLID** principles closely.

EDUCATION

iO Academy

(05/2022 - 09/2022)

Full Stack Track Software Development Bootcamp

PHP, HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, SQL, NodeJS, React, TypeScript, MongoDB, OOP, MVC, Git https://io-academy.uk/courses/full-stack-track/

Marist College (University in New York, USA)

(03/2013 - 03/2017)

BSc, Business Administration (Marketing concentration & Advertising minor with Business Strategy)

EFIA, New York, USA

(03/2011 - 03/2013)

US High School Diploma

WORK EXPERIENCE

Insurance Administrator

(06/2019 - 05/2022)

Expatriate Group

- Managed several business relationships of various sizes and individual clients
- Communicating directly with clients about anything relating to their insurance policy
- QA testing on internal site

Traveling

(05/2018 - 07/2019)

Gap Year

Relocating back to England after being out of the country for a while, also traveling Europe and Norway to reconnect with High School friends and meet new ones.

Operations Analyst Custody Admin (Maternity Cover)

(09/2017 - 05/2018)

Swiss Re, Slovakia

-Member of the Swiss Re Al committee which aimed to automate workplace tasks